<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andy's Blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Andy's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>My name is Andy and I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer and Kubernetes adminstrator.
My main programming language is Python, but I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in Golang and Rust as well.
I live in Bracknell, UK with my wife, Amy, and our 3 kids Kian, Orla and Quinn.</description><content>&lt;p>My name is Andy and I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer and Kubernetes adminstrator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main programming language is Python, but I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in Golang and Rust as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I live in Bracknell, UK with my wife, Amy, and our 3 kids Kian, Orla and Quinn.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="/img/family.jpg" alt="Hello Friend" class="center" style="border-radius: 8px; border: 20px solid var(--accent); padding: 20px" /></content></item><item><title>Curriculum Vitae</title><link>/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cv/</guid><description>Personal Information: Name: Andrew Foston Email: andy &amp;lsquo;at&amp;rsquo; foston.me Date of Birth: 17th August 1982 Driving Licence: Full, clean. LinkedIn Profile: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/andyfoston GitHub Profile: https://github.com/andyfoston Notable Skills: Kubernetes/Istio IaC tools, like: Terraform, Packer &amp;amp; Ansible. Python/Django/Flask Linux Education: 07/05/05 – 21/02/12 BSc (Honours) Open – Open University 30/09/06 – 31/12/08 Diploma in Computing – Open University 07/05/05 – 31/07/06 Certificate in Computing and Mathematics – Open University 2000 – 2001 BTEC HNC Computing and Software Engineering (Incomplete) 1999 – 2000 City &amp;amp; Guilds GNVQ Coding &amp;amp; Programming in ‘c’ Career Summary: Oct 19 - Present day, Tesco Mobile, Slough</description><content>&lt;h3 id="personal-information">Personal Information:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name:&lt;/strong> Andrew Foston&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Email:&lt;/strong> andy &amp;lsquo;at&amp;rsquo; foston.me&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date of Birth:&lt;/strong> 17th August 1982&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Driving Licence:&lt;/strong> Full, clean.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>LinkedIn Profile:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://uk.linkedin.com/in/andyfoston">https://uk.linkedin.com/in/andyfoston&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GitHub Profile:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://github.com/andyfoston">https://github.com/andyfoston&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="notable-skills">Notable Skills:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kubernetes/Istio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IaC tools, like: Terraform, Packer &amp;amp; Ansible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Python/Django/Flask&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linux&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="education">Education:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>07/05/05 – 21/02/12 BSc (Honours) Open – Open University&lt;/li>
&lt;li>30/09/06 – 31/12/08 Diploma in Computing – Open University&lt;/li>
&lt;li>07/05/05 – 31/07/06 Certificate in Computing and Mathematics – Open University&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2000 – 2001 BTEC HNC Computing and Software Engineering (Incomplete)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1999 – 2000 City &amp;amp; Guilds GNVQ Coding &amp;amp; Programming in ‘c’&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="career-summary">Career Summary:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Oct 19 - Present day, Tesco Mobile, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>&lt;strong>Run &amp;amp; Operate Engineer (DevOps Engineer)&lt;/strong>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Solely responsible for supporting AWS infrastructure, including multiple Kubernetes clusters and various EC2 machines using tools like Terraform, Packer and Helm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implementing a service mesh (Istio) for greater visibility and control of traffic passing through the infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deploying updates to tools and Tesco Mobile services.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintaining Jenkins and GitHub actions CI/CD pipelines&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Aug 19 - Oct 19, Tesco Mobile, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Contributing to services used as part of the Tesco Mobile’s sales platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sep 18 - Aug 19, UKCloud Ltd, Farnborough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Software Engineer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developing tools to automate invoice generation and reporting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linux configuration automation using Ansible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completing code reviews for members of my team and for non-developer teams across the business.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration of monitoring tools into a “single pane of glass” monitoring tool using custom extensions written in JavaScript.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mar 16 - Sep 18, Memset Ltd, Cranleigh&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Senior Python Developer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developing tools to automate Linux and network infrastructure configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing new products to offer to our customers.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Notable projects include:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developed a product to support site failover and traffic distribution using BGP to advertise or drop routes based on user-defined health checks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-write of switch VLAN configuration generator to enable unit testing, support for VLANs on LAG groups, multi-chassis LAG and new switch models.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintenance of the Linux firewall configuration generator, and adding features such as policy routing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automating configuration of our new monitoring tool (Zabbix)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apr 15 - Feb 16, iPass UK Ltd, London&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Python Django Developer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developed tools to help deploy new features to all customers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Acted as an escalation point for bug fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automated custom reports for customers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built internal use frameworks to reduce large amounts of boilerplate code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved integration with Django using basic Django features - such as Django forms, messaging, database routers, test runners and fixed 500 error reporting.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Feb 14 - Apr 15, Memset Ltd, Cranleigh&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Python DevOps Engineer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developing and maintaining tools to automate deploying and configuring virtual and physical servers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Migrating legacy Perl scripts to Python and to use Django ORM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Writing unit tests to ensure tools function correctly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Notable projects include&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adding support for Xen virtual servers to be allocated to more than one vLAN (including automating routing, switch and Xen configuration).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adding support for Xen PVHVM virtual machines.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adding support for redundant cabling to physical servers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automate customer penetration testing and reporting using Nessus.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mar 13 – Dec 13, BlackBerry, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>NOC Unix Administrator (3rd line)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Providing 3rd line support to the NOC, and assisting with monitoring and other roles when short-staffed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completing more significant and larger projects to assist the NOC members with troubleshooting common issues within the Blackberry network, including the development of a Python CGI tool to assist with tracing messages through the BlackBerry infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Oct 12 – Mar 13, BlackBerry, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Acting NOC Systems Administrator (3rd line)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Providing 3rd line support to the NOC, and assisting with monitoring and other roles when short-staffed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completing more significant and larger projects to assist the NOC members with troubleshooting common issues within the Blackberry network, including the development of a Python CGI tool to assist with tracing messages through the BlackBerry infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dec 11 – Oct 12, BlackBerry, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>NOC Operations Administrator (2nd line)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provide 2nd line support to &amp;lsquo;NOC Operators&amp;rsquo;, and work on tickets to resolve issues within the prescribed SLAs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take on 1st line roles such as monitoring on occasions such as being short-staffed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Executing pre-planned changes to the Blackberry Network.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Taking an active role on troubleshooting conference calls, by providing information and answers to questions and requests posed by Senior and Specialist members of the team, as well the pro-active investigation of the cause of and impact of these issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Development of Python-based CLI tools to aid investigation of common complaints, as well as to develop a greater understanding of the inner workings of the Blackberry network&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Oct 10 – Dec 11, BlackBerry, Slough&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>NOC Operator (1st line)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Responsible for monitoring the Blackberry Network, as well as resolving known issues as per the documented procedures.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Troubleshooting issues, as well as escalating issues to senior members of the NOC and other specialist teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scheduling troubleshooting conference calls with both external and internal parties.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documenting steps taken by all parties on troubleshooting calls, to be used for establishing the root cause analysis for impacting issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing a command-line Java tool to aid troubleshooting of issues within the Blackberry Network.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apr 09 – Sep 10, 2e2 UK Limited, Reading&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>NOC Engineer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Monitoring of customers’ Cisco Data, Voice and Security products, as well as servers and other IT equipment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Investigation and remote repair of faults; organising field engineers to attend faults that cannot be resolved remotely.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performing daily and nightly tasks, such as LES circuit availability checks, CUCM backup verifications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completing changes on customers’ live equipment, such as static route changes and SNMP configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>